The Long Short-Term Memory cells,
1997年 Sepp Hochreiter 和 Jürgen Schmidhuber 提出了
or LSTM cells, were proposed in 1997 by Sepp Hochreiter and Jürgen Schmidhuber.
长短期记忆单元 又称 LSTM 单元
The goal of the cell is to overcome the vanishing gradient problem.
这个单元的目标是为了解决梯度消失问题
You will see that it allows certain inputs to be latched, or stored,
你会发现它可以长时间锁存或存储特定输入
for long periods of time without forgetting them as would be the case in RNNs.
而不是像循环神经网络一样遗忘它们
When calculating the gradient using backpropagation through time,
使用基于时间的反向传播算法计算梯度时
the gradients stemming back many timessteps can become negligible.
追溯许多时间步长的梯度会变得微不足道
For the same reason,
同样的道理
the partial derivative of the error can also become negligible.
误差的导数也会变得微不足道
This is the fundamental problem in RNNs.
这是循环神经网络的基本问题
You will see that in LSTMs,
你会发现在长短期记忆单元中
we want to avoid the loss of information,
我们想要避免信息损失
or the vanishing gradient problem,
或梯度消失问题
by intentionally latching on to some information over many timesteps.
通过故意锁定许多时间步长中的一些信息
Remembering information over long periods of time is easily achieved using these methods.
利用这些方法可以很容易记忆长时间内的信息
Many real world applications such as Google's language translation tools,
现实世界中许多应用 如谷歌语言翻译工具
or Amazon's Alexa, are powered by LSTMs.
或亚马逊的 Alexa 都是受到 LSTMs 的驱动
In reality, most of the RNN applications we mentioned are
在实际中 我们提到的循环神经网络应用
moving towards implementations using LSTMs.
推动着长短期记忆单元的应用发展
To understand the difference between LSTMs and RNNs,
为了理解长短期记忆单元和循环神经网络的区别
let's look at the RNN system,
我们来看循环神经网络系统
and zoom in on one neuron in a hidden layer,
放大某个隐藏层的神经元
and understand how we calculated S of T plus one.
理解我们如何计算 St+1
Zooming in a bit more will help us remember how the calculations are done.
继续放大可以帮助我们回忆如何得到这些计算
As you may recall,
你可能回想起
the next state was calculated through a simple activation function,
通过一个简单的激活函数 计算下一个状态
let's say a hyperbolic tangent,
例如双曲正切
of a linear combination of different inputs,
不同输入
and their corresponding weight matrices.
及其对应权重矩阵的线性组合
The output was calculated as a simple linear combination as well.
通过一个简单的线性组合也可以计算得到输出
Using LSTMs, we no longer have basic computations as we had here in a single neuron.
我们通过使用长短期记忆单元 不再只是像这里只有一个神经元时的简单运算
Zooming out again, our system will have a very similar layout.
通过再次缩小 我们的系统布局非常类似
The neurons of the hidden states are replaced with LSTM cells,
隐藏状态的神经元替代为长短期记忆单元
and can be stacked like lego pieces, just as before.
可以跟之前一样 像乐高积木一样堆叠起来
If we zoom in on one cell,
如果放大一个单元
we will find that we no longer have a single calculation,
我们会发现不再是一个单独的计算
but we have four separate ones.
而是有四个单独的计算
This is our LSTM cell,
这是我们的长短期记忆单元
this is our first calculation,
这是我们的第一个计算
our second, our third,
第二个 第三个
and finally, the fourth.
和第四个计算
The LSTM network allows a recurrent system to learn over
长短期记忆单元网络让循环的系统
many timesteps while training the network using the same backpropagation principles.
在许多时间步长中学习 同时使用相同的反向传播原则训练网络
In these cases, we are no longer considering a few timesteps back as we did in RNNs,
在这些例子中 我们不再只是像循环神经网络中那样 只追溯少数几个时间步长
but can consider over 1,000.
而是要考虑 1000 多个时间步长
The cell is fully differentiable, meaning,
这个单元是完全可以微分的
that all of its functions have a gradient or a derivative that we can calculate.
也就是说所有函数都有我们可以计算的梯度或导数
These functions are a sigmoid,
这些函数包括 sigmoid
a hyperbolic tangent, multiplication, and addition.
双曲正切 乘法和加法
This allows us to use backpropagation,
这可以让我们使用反向传播算法
or stochastic gradient descent,
或随机梯度下降
when updating the weights.
更新权重
The main idea with LSTM cells,
长短期记忆单元的主要观点是
is that they can decide which information to remove or forget,
它们可以决定删除或遗忘哪些信息
which information to store,
存储哪些信息
and when to use it.
以及何时使用这些信息
The cell can also help decide when to move the previous states information to the next.
这个单元也可以帮助确定何时从之前的状态信息移到下一个状态
We just saw that the LSTM cell has three sigmoids.
我们刚刚看到长短期记忆单元包括三个 sigmoid
The output of each sigmoid is between zero and one.
每个 sigmoid 的输出都在 0 到 1 之间
Having the data flow through a sigmoid intuitively answers the following questions.
通过这个 sigmoid 得到数据流动可以直接回答下列问题
Do we let all the data flow through when the output of the sigmoid is one,
sigmoid 输出为 1 时或接近 1 时 我们能不能让
or close to it?
所有数据流动呢？
Or do we force the output to be a zero,
另外没有数据流动时
where none of the data flows through.?
输出必须为 0 吗？
And that would be if the output of the sigmoid is zero, or close to it.
如果 sigmoid 输出为 0 或接近 0 可能是这样的
These three sigmoids act as a mechanism to filter what goes into the cell,
这三个 sigmoid 发挥了过滤进入单元内容的作用
if at all, what is retained within the cell,
即单元保留什么
and what passes through to its output.
哪些可以传递到输出
The key idea in LSTMs is that these three gating functions are
长短期记忆单元的关键要点是
also trained using backpropagation by adjusting the weights that feed into them.
使用反向传播算法 通过调整添加的权重 也可以训练这三个门控函数
Our next set of videos will help you understand LSTMs further.
我们接下来的视频会帮助你进一步理解长短期记忆单元